漫威影业出品
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
■
翻译：铁链斯嘉丽  夜魔开
翻译：夜魔克里斯  腋毛暴徒
校对：夜魔奶
躺下  马特  别起来
Stay down, Matty. Don't get up.
时间轴：夜魔安  萌  夜瞎查
后期：聪炒吉丁  8T     总监：夜魔奶
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
你需要休息
You need rest.
早上好  帅哥
Morning, sunshine.
夜
魔
侠
第二季  第三集
最好有人把我的车开过来
Someone better be getting my car.
邦迪五分钟后到
Bundy's five minutes out.
别让媒体进来
Keep the press out of here.
清理好现场前不许发表声明也不允许拍照
No statements or photos until we get this place spotless.
-我们要控制舆论  -您放心
- We control the narrative. - Of course.
你离开以前
And before you leave,
尼尔森先生和佩吉小姐有话要说
Mr. Nelson and Miss Page wanted a word.
非要说吗  不能写下来吗
Ugh. Just one? Can I get that in writing?
现在才意识到书面协议的重要性
Oh, because written agreements suddenly mean something to you?
你想把你的委托人列入证人保护计划吧
You wanted your client in witness protection, right?
我提议还有23分钟才失效
My offer's still valid for 23 minutes.
-格罗托不见了  -太遗憾了
- Grotto's gone. - Too bad.
你把我们的委托人当成了诱饵
You used our client for bait!
这指控可不是闹着玩的...
That's a pretty big allegation--
指控
Allegation?
你好好看看  这次多惊险  他差点就死了
Look around! This was a shit show! He could have died.
打开天窗说亮话吧
Let's be real honest here.
不说废话
No bullshit.
你这律所微不足道
Your firm is small-time.
之前那起大案子的风头也过去了
Your 15 minutes were up after Union Allied.
你现在这样就是太自不量力了
Right now, you are way out of your league.
我不用费什么功夫
Won't take much to sell
就能让大家相信是你们破坏了这次行动
that you're the ones that compromised this operation.
-你说什么  -假如这事闹得世人皆知
- What? - Say that story goes public.
假如人们知道
The story that your
你因不称职而让你的委托人
incompetence endangered the life of your client,
街坊邻居以及纽约警局勇敢警员的生命受到威胁
neighborhood civilians, and the brave officers of the NYPD.
你的意思是你要把现在这局面怪到我们头上
You are saying that you would blame us for this?
我从没这么说过  我说过这话吗
I never said that. Did I say that?
我没听到
I didn't hear it.
这案子你别插手
Stay away from this case.
不吭声  连点声援都没有
Nothing? Hmm? Not even a little support?
这种事走正路是行不通的
All the legal kung fu in the world wouldn't have won that fight.
当局能轻松除掉我们
Her office could bury us.
我们不该这么急躁
We shouldn't have pushed it.
是啊  急躁的事都是我干的
Yeah, well, you didn't push anything.
我明白这些混蛋是怎么办事的
I know how these assholes operate.
眼下  只能按照他们的方式来
We have to play it their way. Just for now.
那接下来呢
But then what next?
马特向格罗托保证过  我们会保护他
All right, Matt promised Grotto we would protect him,
我也保证过
so did I!
我这就给马特打电话
I'm gonna call Matt now.
看他是否...有体力帮我们
Let's see if he's... recuperated enough to help us out.
好吧  那我这就回律所去
All right, I'm gonna go back to the office.
看能不能
I'm gonna see if I can
想办法不让雷耶斯活剥了我们
find a way that Reyes doesn't skin us alive.
都说子弹打中你的时候是听不到声音的
They say you don't hear the bullet that gets you.
我还以为是胡说八道的
Always thought that sounded like a bunch of bullshit to me.
你呢  小红
How about you, Red?
那天晚上我打碎了你额头...
When I cracked off your forehead the other night...
你听到声了吗
did you hear that?
你可以挣脱个一整晚
You can bash against your chains all night.
但想要离开这里
Only way you get out of here,
获得自由的前提是取得我的同意
only way you walk free, is if I want you to.
你要清楚这一点
Know that.
你为什么没摘掉我的面具
Why didn't you take my mask off?
我才不在乎你是谁
Don't give a shit about who you are.
你把其他人都杀了
You killed everyone else.
为什么不杀掉我
Why am I still alive?
我已经两次碍你事了...
I got in your way twice now...
我感觉你不像是任由这种事发生的人
and you don't strike me as someone who just lets that happen.
军用级别的武器
Military grade hardware.
看样子你很熟悉
You seem to know your way around it.
反正你看上去像是个军人
And you sure carry yourself like a soldier.
你要用这些武器干什么
What are you gonna do with all this?
完成使命
I'll do what's required.
我们都等六个小时了
We've been waiting six hours!
拜托了  小姐  拜托
Come on, lady. Come on!
克莱尔  真该死  接电话啊
Claire, damn it, pick up.
如果你听到留言的话  来急诊室找我
If you get this, I'm in the ER.
有事跟你说
We need to talk.
我靠
Holy shit.
你为什么总找我麻烦
Why don't you stop hassling me
而不追究打我哥们的那个疯子呢
and go after the psycho who blew away my crew!
就是他  就是那家伙
That's him! That's the guy!
打扰一下  我想找克莱尔护士
Excuse me, I'm looking for a nurse named Claire?
我记得她上的是夜班
I believe she works the night shift.
她在  但她很忙
If she's here, she's busy.
那能告诉我去哪能找到她吗
Could you just point me in the right direction?
-你受伤了吗  -没有
- Are you injured? - No.
那你希望我揍你吗
Do you wanna be?
卡弗先生  到你了
Mr. Carver? We can see you now.
为什么还让我等
Why you telling me to wait?
一小时以前你就这么说
You've been telling me this for like an hour already.
别碰我  我没交代
Hey, get your hands off me! I didn't say nothin'. Come on!
拜托了  那是我哥们  他被人偷袭了
Oh, man, that's our boy. He got jumped.
急诊
我认识你堂兄  我知道你住哪
I know your cousin. I know where you live.
不  全怪他
No, he's no good.
我坐的好好的  不是我起头的
I'm sittin', man, all right? I'm not startin' nothin'.
别激动  好吗
Just relax, all right?
-这就是你的答案  -这话我不会再重复了
- That's what you tell me? - I'm not gonna tell you again.
-闭嘴  坐下  -不是我们起头的
- Quiet! Sit down! - Yeah? We're not startin' nothin', man!
是他挑事的
He's the one that started it,
-懂了吗  -再这样你就滚吧
- All right? - You keep it up, you're out of here.
你死定了  出门你就废了
You're a dead man, you understand? As soon as you get out.
注意听
Hey, listen up.
警察正等着收押你
Police are waiting to take you into custody.
我不希望你两周以后回医院来
The last thing I need is for you to come back here in two weeks,
质问今晚的事
asking what happened,
把责任推到我们工作人员身上
and blaming one of our people for your mistakes.
我也不跟你绕弯子了
Hey, so let me put this simply.
昨天  你还有五根手指
Yesterday, you had five fingers.
但是今晚  你全副武装
But tonight, you got loaded
决定去袭击对方的大本营
and decided to hit up a rival clubhouse.
现在你只剩两根了
So now you have two.
这是战争  女士
We're at war, lady.
听我说
Listen to me.
原来有五根  现在只剩两根
Had five. Now two.
都怪你自己  明白了吗
Your fault. That clear?
很好
Good.
药效应该很快就上来了
The meds should kick in soon.
克莱尔
Claire.
福吉·尼尔森  我们有一个共同的朋友
Foggy Nelson. We have a mutual friend.
还记得我吗
Remember me?
该死
Shit.
助理检察官艾略特·詹姆斯因丑闻辞职
尼尔森-默多克律所  你好
Nelson and Murdock, may I help you?
到底怎么回事
What the hell was that?
格罗托
Grotto?
格罗托  你在哪儿
Grotto, where are you?
你出了这种事还指望我会告诉你吗
Like I'd tell you shit after what went down.
-你受伤了吗  -少管这些
- Are you hurt? - Forget all that.
你到底帮不帮我
You gonna help me out or not?
-当然了  我们会努力...  -努力
- Uh, yeah, uh, we'll try-- - Try?
听着  相信我
Look, you have to believe me,
我们根本不知道雷耶斯想干什么
we had no idea what Reyes was planning--
闭嘴  闭嘴  该死的律师  你们都一样
Shut up! Shut up! Goddamn lawyers, you're all alike.
动动嘴皮子  说得天花乱坠
Runnin' your mouths, all that fancy talk...
尽坑我这样的人
All the time you're just stickin' it to guys like me.
-格罗托...  -你下过很多承诺
- Grotto-- - You made promises, lady!
结果都被你自己一个个打破了
You broke every one of 'em.
我知道
I know.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
听着  格罗托  警察在到处找你
Listen, Grotto, the police are coming after you.
你得来自首
You have to come in.
那些枪声  都是...都是因为他吧
All that shootin', it was... it was 'cause of him, wasn't it?
那个医院里的疯子
The psycho from the hospital?
-是的  -该死
- Yeah. - Shit.
该死  他不会罢手的
Shit. He's never gonna stop.
听着  地检知道自己搞砸了
Look, the DA knows she screwed up.
我们可以去找她  可以坚持证人保护...
We can go back to her. We can lock in witness protection--
我不要再做辩诉协议了  亲爱的
I'm done makin' deals, sweetheart.
我现在有自己的计划
I've got my own plan now,
趁我还有一口气  我要离开这个地狱
gettin' outta this hellhole while I'm still breathin'.
你告诉那个胖律师和那个瞎子
You tell that donut of a lawyer and the blind man,
让他们见鬼去吧
they can kiss my ass.
格罗托  别...
Grotto, please--
你去死吧
You can go to hell.
这是你的另一项任务吗
This another one of your missions?
所以我们才要来这里
That's why we're here, isn't it?
这次要杀多少人
How many will this make?
我猜你已经做过...
I'm guessing you've done this, what...
十几二十几次了吧
ten, maybe 20 times?
多久了
How long's it been?
六个月  一年
Six months, a year...
还是说一辈子
or your whole life?
我感觉你好像从来不休息
Something tells me you don't take breaks.
没必要再杀人
You know, no one else has to die.
你现在还能收手
You could stop now.
就此离开
Walk away.
Walk away?
你做得到吗
Could you do that?
你能就此离开吗
Could you walk away?
我就说嘛
Yeah.
什么声音  半夜了吗
What is that, midnight?
圣马修教堂
St. Matthew's.
你是天主教徒吗
You a Catholic?
曾经是
Once.
纽约人吗
From New York?
曾经是
Once.
你还会去做弥撒吗
You still go to Mass?
别问了  小红
Stop now, Red.
-什么别问  -别深究了
- Stop? - Stop digging.
纽约有个非常有趣的特点...
You know, a funny thing about New York...
只有少数人是本地人
few people are actually from here.
那些本地人
The ones who are...
他们离不开  他们做不到  他们...
they don't leave. They can't, they, uh...
他们感觉这座城市已经成为他们的一部分
They feel like the city's a part of them.
你知道吗
You know?
直到有一天  有些事变了  也许他们长大了
Until one day, something changes. Maybe they get older.
然后他们得离开  他们得离开这里
And then they have to leave, they have to get out.
也许要去看看世界
See the world, maybe.
也许入了伍
Maybe they enlist?
他们派你去哪儿了
Where'd they send you?
你是个心理医生吗  小红
You a shrink, Red?
说吧  你没穿连体衣的时候
Now, come on, you must be something
肯定也有自己的生活吧
when you're not wearing the long johns, right?
-我只是个无名小卒  -是吗
- I'm just a guy. - Yeah?
你上过战场吗
You ever been to war?
没有
No.
是吗...那就别提这个话题
Yeah... then don't talk about it.
我见过不少争斗
I've seen some fights.
我想也是
Sure you have.
我差点打败了你
Well, I almost had you beat.
你在这屋顶上跟我讲大道理  小红
You talk about trading hands on a rooftop, Red.
战争其实是那么不幸
I'm talking about shit, okay?
你从未经历过如此不幸的事
Shit that you ain't been in.
-我只知道一件事  -什么事
- I know one thing. - What's that?
战争会改变人
War changes people.
让他们无法忘记那些惨状
Sometimes they see things they can't unsee.
回到家发现自己的家园已经不在
Come home to find home's not there anymore.
已经变了
It changed.
或许是他们变了
Or maybe they did.
有道理
Yeah, fair enough.
我只是想说  我知道那很痛苦
I'm just saying, I know it can be hard.
是吗
Do you?
你知道那很痛苦
You know it can be hard?
你穿套小屁孩儿的
You run around this city
睡衣和一副面具在城里跑来跑去
in a pair of little boy's pajamas and a mask.
你晚上会回家的  对吧
You go home at night, right?
摘掉面具  也许你想着
Take that mask off, maybe you think...
做那些事儿的人并不是你  也许是别人
it wasn't you who did those things, maybe it was somebody else.
可你看士兵们
Well, see, soldiers...
我们不戴面具
we don't wear masks, yeah?
我们没那种特权
We don't get that privilege.
-你知道我怎么想的吗  -怎么想的
- You know what I think? - What's that?
-你还在想着打仗  -我的天啊
- You're still at war. - Oh, for crying out loud.
你是按小时收费的吗  医生
So, you charge by the hour, doc, or what?
我为什么会在这儿
Why am I here?
小红  你在外面搞的那些名堂没用
Everything you do out there in the streets, Red, it doesn't work.
-你知道吗  -你做的就更管用吗
- Did you know that? - Oh, and what you're doing is better?
我该出手时就出手  都是有必要的
What I do, I just do. It's out of necessity.
得了吧
Come on.
你知道你不是唯一的吧
You know you're not the only one, right?
你失去了谁
Who did you lose?
是你爱过的人吗
Was it someone you loved?
得了吧  我来告诉你吧  哥们
Well, boo-hoo. Let me tell you something, buddy.
谁都失去过  那并不意味着你非得这么做
Everybody's lost someone. Doesn't mean you have to do this.
对于每个人来说失去的意义不同  小红
Well, loss doesn't work the same for everybody, Red.
是啊没错  显然这让你很难适应
Yeah, that's right. It's clearly not working for you.
也许是吧
Maybe not.
小红  我们无法选择什么能治愈我们
We don't get to pick the things that fix us, Red.
什么能让我们完整
Make us whole.
什么能让我们有目标
Make us feel purpose.
我的彻悟呢  来自于那些最奇怪的地方
My moment of clarity? It came from the strangest of places.
地狱厨房恶魔算什么名号
What kind of name is The Devil of Hell's Kitchen, anyway?
搞什么
I mean, really?
我可不想叫这个名字
I didn't ask for that name.
抱歉  我也没见你嫌弃这名字
I'm sorry, I don't see you running from it.
我这么做不是为了伤害人们
I don't do this to hurt people.
-那为了什么  做义警有好处吗  -我不杀人
- Yeah, so what is that, just a job perk? - I don't kill anyone.
所以你才觉得你比我高尚吗
Is that why you think you're better than me?
-不是  -所以你觉得自己是个大英雄吗
- No. - Is that why you think you're a big hero?
我怎么想或者我是什么样的人都不重要
It doesn't matter what I think or what I am.
人们没必要死
People don't have to die.
行了  小红  你真那么想吗
Come on, Red. You believe that?
我相信这不能由我来决定  也轮不到你
I believe it's not my call, and it ain't yours either.
是有人让你穿上那套紧身衣
Somebody ask you to put on that costume
还是你自己要穿的
or you take it upon yourself?
你知道我怎么想你的吗  大英雄
You know what I think of you, hero?
我觉得你是个半吊子
I think you're a half-measure.
我觉得你是个有始无终的人
I think you're a man who can't finish the job.
我觉得你是个懦夫
I think that you're a coward.
你知道你没看明白什么事吗
You know the one thing that you just can't see?
你知道你哪天受够了也会变成我这样
You know you're one bad day away from being me.
是啊
Yeah.
有人来了
Someone's coming.
妈的
Shit.
-看来我最好躲一下  -别伤害他
- Guess I'd better make a run for it. - Hey, don't hurt him.
是吗  那祈祷他不会给我这样做的理由吧
Yeah? Let's hope he doesn't give me a reason to.
吵吵闹闹的怎么回事
What's all that noise?
如果又是你们这群死孩子  我发誓我会报警的
If it's you damned kids again, I swear I'm callin' the cops!
我就说一次  小红
I'll say this once, Red.
你敢弄出一点动静
You make one sound,
我就让他的脑袋在这个屋顶开花
and I'll open his head up all over this roof.
有人吗
Hello?
现在可不是时候
This is really not a good time.
-这儿怎么回事  -自己看啊
- What's going on in here? - You tell me.
-病人把四个走廊都挤满了  -我明白
- I have patients stacked up in four halls. - Look, I get it.
你眼下忙得手忙脚乱
You're up to your eyeballs.
但我也遇到了困难
But I got a problem too,
但如果不是急事我也不会来这儿
and I wouldn't be here if it wasn't good and goddamn urgent.
我在找一个我们共同的朋友
I'm looking for a certain mutual friend of ours.
小心点  贱人
Careful, bitch.
我没见过他  这个月我都在急诊室值班
I haven't seen him. I've been on ER duty all month.
没休息  我最近
No breaks. I haven't been
连这些走廊都出不去
able to walk outside of these walls lately.
听起来你好像惹到了某些人
Sounds like you pissed somebody off.
是啊  那我最拿手了
Yeah, I'm getting really good at that.
你敢撕开  你就自己再缝上吧
You rip that, you're gonna have to re-stitch it yourself.
这么说他没来过这儿
So he hasn't been here?
他为什么会来这儿
He have a reason to be?
你也知道我们的朋友钟爱极限运动
Well, you know, our friend is fond of extreme sports.
别废话了  我知道你说得是谁
You can cut the shit. I know who you're talking about.
我想着也许他又来找你帮忙了
I thought maybe he came to you for help again.
上次他找我帮忙
The last time he came to me for help,
我双手都沾满了这位共同朋友的血
I wound up elbow deep in our mutual friend's blood.
那事儿我绝对不再干了
I'm never doing that again.
好吧  也许你能帮我查查记录
Well, maybe you can help me check records.
看看他是不是去其他地方了
See if he's come in anywhere else.
听着
Look...
我知道你为什么这么担心
I know why you're worried.
可他最近名声可大了
He's been building himself quite the rep lately.
这是我想听到的消息吗
Is this something I want to hear?
女士  我现在要去哪
Yo, lady, where the hell am I supposed to go now?
你想知道急诊室的意见吗
You want the ER perspective?
受害者爱他
Victims love him.
致害人呢
Victimizers?
比从前更想让他去死了
Want him more dead than ever.
如果你要跟着我的话
Look, if you're gonna follow me around...
至少让自己管点用
at least make yourself useful.
给
Here...
看着桌子另一边
look around the other side of the table.
我不知道我有没有资格这样做
I'm not sure I'm qualified for this.
你喘着气儿  没被拷着  你就能做
You're breathing, you're not in cuffs, you're on the team.
我说喷就喷
Spray when I say.
我在乎我们的朋友
Look, I care about our friend.
我相信他所做的事  我相信这个城市需要他
I believe in what he's doing, I believe the city needs him.
但事实是  我再也帮不上忙了
But the truth is, I can't help anymore.
我忙得团团转
I've got this shift from hell
是因为我帮了另一位想做好事的朋友
'cause I helped another friend trying to do good.
大个子
Big guy.
比我们那位朋友更强壮
stronger than our friend.
但我自己却倒霉了
And yet I'm the one who got the shaft.
我只是想保持低调  做好本职工作
I'm just trying to keep my head down, do my job...
保持清醒  给他喷上
Stay sane. Spray.
相信我  我和你一样不想掺和这件事
Trust me, I don't like being a part of this any more than you do.
但我需要找到他
But I need to find him.
我想自己去  但我已经想不出办法了
I'd do it myself, but I'm out of ideas.
听着  尽管他处境危险  马特...
Listen, as close as he gets, Matt's...
总是能想办法死里逃生
pretty good at not getting himself killed.
这一点我现在不那么确定了
I'm not so sure about that anymore.
放松点  蠢货  我的腿疼死了
Easy, dumb-ass. My leg is killing me.
你最近接诊了不少送到前就死亡的病人啊
So, you've probably been pulling in lots of DOAs lately.
都是罪犯
Criminal types?
最近枪伤病人的数量比之前大大增加
There's been a serious uptick in gunshot wounds,
既然你提到了
now that you mention it.
看来有什么事把黑帮惹火了
Something's really got the gangs riled.
应该说是"某人"
It's a "Someone."
而挑起这件事的家伙正是马特的敌人
And the freak responsible is the one Matt's up against.
我保证这就走人  但是拜托...
I'll be out of your hair before you know it, but, please...
他是我最好的朋友
he's my best friend.
我只想确保他一切还好
I just need to make sure he's okay.
你个混蛋  让我看看你的本事  来吧
You son of a bitch! See what you got, punk! Come on!
来啊  过来
Come on, get over here!
我要把你的头砸烂
I'll crack your stupid head open!
-快叫警卫过来  -冷静点
- Somebody call security. - Calm down!
你他妈是谁
Who the hell are you?
弗兰克
Frank.
你在这做什么  弗兰克
What are you doing up here, Frank?
说实话  我确信这个屋顶
Well, the truth is, um, I'm pretty sure that this here roof,
就在这里  这是...
right here, this is the, uh...
这里是美国的
this is the last patch of
最后一块土地
real estate in the entire goddamn United States
在这里人们可以自己一个人安安静静地待着
where a man can just have a little peace, be by himself, and...
抽支烟
have a smoke.
在这附近从没见过你
Never seen you around.
是啊  我刚进城来看我那个疯姐姐
Yeah, no. I'm, uh, in town just visiting my crazy sister.
住2B的贝蒂
Betty in 2B?
看来你领教过她的厉害
I see you've had the pleasure.
-我不怪你  -是啊
- Can't say I blame you. - Nah.
我妻子也是  劝我戒烟很久了
My wife's the same. Made me quit a long time ago.
你知道人们都怎么说
You know what they say.
是为了我们健康着想
It's for our health.
难道我们就不该享受生活了吗
What about the enjoyment of life?
可能他们死的时候才会考虑享福吧
Guess they'll worry about that when they're dead.
那是什么
What was that?
只是...只是一只老鼠
Uh, it's just... just a rat.
我们灭过鼠啊
We exterminated.
很多人...总是草草了事
Lot of guys... they half-ass it.
记得我叔叔总对我这么说
Remember my uncle used to tell me that all the time.
他用烟熏
He fumigated.
很辛苦啊
Hard work.
是啊  战争过后他只能以此谋生了
Yeah, well. It's all he could get after the war.
你懂的  士兵的诅咒
You know, curse of a soldier.
可不是么
Ain't that the truth.
是啊  你服过役
Yeah. You serve?
在越南  第三陆战师
'Nam, 3rd Marine Division.
拼命三师啊
Fighting 3rd, huh?
对极了  你呢
Goddamn right. You?
伊拉克  阿富汗
Yeah, yeah. Iraq, Afghanistan.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
谢谢你  先生
Thank you, sir.
我得赶紧下去了  不过你...
I gotta go down right now, but,
你想抽多少烟都可以  孩子
you...you smoke as much as you like, son.
-谢谢  先生  -回见  孩子
- Thank you, sir. All right. - All right, son.
-老兵  -什么事
- Hey, Marine! - Yeah?
永远忠诚
Semper Fi.
弗兰克
Frank.
那是你的真名吗
That's your real name?
-你开始威胁无辜的人了吗  -他有危险
- You get off threatening innocent people? - He was only in danger
是因为你出声了  你不服从指令
because you squealed, because you can't follow orders--
你用枪指着他  你已经扣住了扳机
You had a gun on him. You thumbed back the hammer.
那是演给你看的  表演的一部分
Yeah, well, that was for you. Part of the show.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
真用我给你解释清楚是吗  小红
I really have to spell it out for you, Red? Huh?
我好失望  给我听清了  好吗
I'm disappointed. Listen carefully, okay?
你在听吗  现在呢
You listening? Yeah? How 'bout now?
你在听吗  你感觉到了吗
You listening? Feel it?
我不是坏人  小红
I'm not a bad guy, Red.
你想去跟那些被你
You wanna explain that to the
害成孤儿和寡妇的人解释吗
orphans and the widows of the men you killed?
上帝啊  你是这样想的
For Christ's sake, that's what you think?
我就个发疯的混蛋
I'm just some crazy asshole
到处随便找人发泄
going around unloading on whoever I want to?
对  我就是这么想的
Yeah, that's exactly what I think.
-就这样  -你以为你是什么人
- That it? - You think you're anything else?
我认为我杀的人都是罪有应得
I think that the people I kill need killing,
我是这样想的
that's what I think.
你把一个活人挂在铁钩上
You left men hanging from meat hooks!
我觉得  那样算便宜他们了
They got off easy, in my opinion.
你在一家医院里乱射一通
You shot up a hospital.
是的  但无辜的人一个都没受伤
Yeah, and nobody got hurt who didn't deserve it.
是啊  那你呢  弗兰克
Oh, yeah. What about you, Frank?
如果有天让别人来决定你是不是罪有应得呢
What happens the day someone decides you deserve it?
那他们最好别失手
I'll tell you what, they better not miss.
得了吧  你在这座城市四处出没
Come on, you run around this city
好像是你的靶场一样
like it's your damn shooting gallery.
-你觉得...  -那你呢  你又做了什么
- You think you do-- - Yeah, what do you do? What do you do?
你把它当成游乐场
You act like it's a playground.
你赤手空拳把恶棍痛揍一顿
You beat up the bullies with your fists.
把他们扔进监狱  别人都把你当做英雄
You throw 'em in jail, everybody calls you a hero, right?
然后一个月  一周  甚至一天后
And then a month, a week, a day later,
-他们又回到街上做着和之前一样的事  -没错
- they're back on the streets doing the same goddamn thing  - Yeah,
所以你就置他们于死地
so you just put 'em in the morgue.
你说得太对了  我就是这样做的
You're goddamn right, I do.
-你怀疑过自己吗  弗兰克  -从来没有
- You ever doubt yourself, Frank? - Not even for a second.
真的吗  真的吗  你从来没有想过
Really? Really? You never think for one second,
"该死  我刚杀了一个人"
"Shit, I just killed a human being."
你说得真委婉
That's being pretty generous.
一个做了很多蠢事的人  甚至非常邪恶
A human being who did a lot of stupid shit, maybe even evil,
但内心可能还有一丝良善
but had one small piece of goodness in him.
也许只有一点  弗兰克  但仍存有善念
Maybe just a scrap, Frank, but something.
然后你出现了  那一点光明的火苗
And then you come along, and that one tiny flicker of light
永远被你掐灭了
gets snuffed out forever.
我觉得你错了
I think you're wrong.
-哪一部分  -全错了
- Which part? - All of it.
我认为我干掉的人渣心中没有善
I think there's no good in the filth that I put down,
我是这么认为的
that's what I think.
-你怎么知道的  -我就是知道
- And how do you know? - I just know.
看看四周  小红  这座城市像下水道般恶臭
Look around, Red. This city, it stinks. It's a sewer.
简直臭不可闻
It stinks and it smells like shit
我一直能闻到这股恶臭
and I can't get the stink out of my nose.
我认为这个世界
I think that this world,
需要能够狠下心肠作出决定的人
it needs men that are willing to make the hard call.
我觉得你和我一样
I think you and me are the same!
那简直是胡扯  弗兰克  你自己很清楚
That's bullshit, Frank, and you know it!
但是我能做到你做不到的事
Only I do the one thing that you can't.
你打倒他们  他们会卷土重来
You hit 'em, and they get back up.
我干掉他们  他们不会东山再起
I hit 'em, and they stay down.
永远不会  我会确保
It's permanent. I make sure
他们永远不会再出现在街头小巷
that they don't make it out on the street again.
这让我很骄傲
I take pride in that.
-让我问问你  -你要问什么
- Let me ask you this. - What's that?
-希望呢  -该死
- What about hope? - Oh, fuck.
-说啊  弗兰克  -你还想和我聊圣诞老人吧
- Come on, Frank-- - You wanna talk about Santa Claus?
你想和我聊圣诞老人吗
You wanna talk about Santa Claus?
我也活在这个世界  我亲眼看到过
I live in the real world too, and I've seen it.
-是吗  你看到过什么  -救赎  弗兰克
- Yeah? What have you seen? - Redemption, Frank.
-上帝啊  -真的  会出现这种事
- Ah, Jesus Christ. - It's real. And it's possible.
你杀的那些人应该拥有第二次机会
The people you murder deserve another chance.
让他们再次杀戮奸淫吗  这是你想看到的吗
What, to kill again? Rape again? Is that what you want?
不  弗兰克  再次努力  弗兰克
No, Frank. To try again, Frank.
努力
To try.
如果你没法理解
And if you don't get that,
那就说明你内心中有无法填补的缺陷
there's something broken in you you can't fix,
你真的是个疯子
and you really are a nutjob.
你说什么
What did you say?
你...
You're...
你疯了...弗兰克
You're unhinged... Frank.
没错
You are.
你以为上帝让你成为了一个孤胆英雄
You think God made you a one-man firing squad.
但是你错了
But you're wrong.
人性中有善  连你也是
There is goodness in people, even in you.
你不得不杀了我
And you're gonna have to kill me,
因为我不会停止追寻你的步伐
'cause I'm never gonna stop coming for you,
直到我打倒你
until I take you down.
-你想知道为什么吗  -为什么呢
- You wanna know why? - Why's that?
因为你疯了
Because you're insane.
加班了
Late night?
你在这儿干什么
What are you doing here?
保护我们的委托人  他现在仍孤身在外
Protecting our client, who is still out there, alone.
你把他说得好像一条...走失的小狗
You're talking about him like he's a... a lost puppy.
格罗托先生是一名罪犯
Mr. Grote is a convicted criminal
我们给过他机会了
and lucky we gave him the time of day.
换我是你就不会再管他了
I'd forget about him if I were you.
我们保证过会保护他
We promised to protect him.
也许你就不该保证
Maybe you shouldn't have.
你的上司说她能轻松
Your boss said she could take down
搞垮我们这样的律所
a firm like ours pretty quickly.
她没说错
She wasn't lying.
所以她也能搞垮你这样的人吗
So, she could also take down someone like you?
助理检察官艾略特·詹姆斯
ADA Elliot James.
因一年前在泰勒案中为雷耶斯
Took the fall after Reyes mishandled informants
担下了处理线人不当的罪名
in the, uh, Teller case about a year ago.
妮可·肯特由于未能压住
Nicole Kent got booted from your office
安森丑闻而被解职
after she failed to quiet the EnSynth scandal.
克里斯·大卫森
Chris Davidson...
你见过他吗
did you ever meet him?
因为派尔案中国家最高法院
Fired after the State Supreme Court
因"普遍存在不正当行为"
disqualified your entire office
而取消你们办公室的公诉资格而被解雇
from the Pell case due to "Widespread misconduct."
"普遍存在"
"Widespread."
但其他人都没有被解雇
But not everyone got fired.
雷耶斯片叶不沾身
See, Reyes walked out in one piece.
她非常擅长拿别人来顶罪
She's good at throwing people to the wolves.
没错  她这个月能搞垮尼尔森-默多克律所
So, sure, she can take down Nelson and Murdock this month,
但是你
but how long
还有多久就会跟我们一样被拖下水呢
before you are getting pulled into the shit with the rest of us?
你想吓唬我
You trying to scare me?
我是来告诉你  你和雷耶斯
I am here to show you that you and Reyes
不是同一战壕里的人
are not on the same team.
你到底上哪儿找到的这些资料
Where would you even find this shit?
我希望对尼尔森-默多克律所进行保护
I want protection for Nelson and Murdock.
我们规模很小
We're small.
出点岔子就完蛋了
We can't survive getting thrown to the wolves.
除非你帮忙
Not without your help.
今天发生了这么多事  有人会就此完蛋
After what happened today, someone's gonna crash and burn
我需要确保完蛋的不是我们
and I need to know that that won't be us.
就算我想帮你  你为什么认为我能帮你
What makes you think I can help you, even if I wanted to?
-你有关于惩罚者的情报  -这是机密
- You have information on the Punisher. - That's classified.
我看上去像是会把这些信息发布在网上的人吗
Do I look like I'm gonna post it on YouTube?
你的上司威胁要吊销我朋友的执照
Your boss is threatening to disbar my friends
并搞垮我们的公司
and dismantle our law firm.
我上司是挺难缠的
Yeah, my boss is a piece of work.
假设真的有惩罚者的资料  那又怎么能
Look, how will the Punisher files, assuming they even exist,
帮你阻止这一切呢
help you stop that from happening?
到时候你就知道了
I'll let you know.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
你要我把检察官拉下水
So, you expect me to implicate the DA on purpose?
给我听好了
Listen very carefully.
你不能就这么走进我的办公室
You cannot come into my office,
要我背叛我的上司
asking me to betray my boss,
向我胡说一通你自己根本就
throwing around allegations about this department
无法证实的指控
you cannot substantiate.
我要下楼叫保安了
So I'm going downstairs to get security.
你不许再联系我
And you will not contact me again.
不许发邮件  不许打电话  什么都不行
No emails. No phone calls. Nothing.
晚安  佩吉小姐
Good night, Miss Page.
-你死定了  -去死吧
- You're dead! - Go to hell!
他们发现弗莱迪·博恩斯胸前中了十枪
They found Freddie Bones with ten slugs to his chest!
不是我们干的  混蛋
That wasn't us, prick.
-这种事经常发生吗  -这周太糟糕了
- This happen often? - It's been a bad week.
该死
Shit.
-放下  放下  -退后
- Put it down! Put it down! - Back off!
这里有无辜的人
There's innocent people here!
这事跟你们没关系
This ain't got nothin' to do with you.
你会伤到人的
You're gonna hurt somebody.
我不会说第二遍  快放下
I'm not gonna tell you again. Put it down, now!
混蛋  你有多少前科
Hey, asshole. How many priors you got?
你说什么
What'd you say to me?
我问你有多少前科
I asked you about your priors.
你就继续胡说八道吧
Yeah, keep talking shit.
我保证亲自送你进重症监护室
I'll check you into ICU myself.
你脸上有刺青  朋友
You got face tattoos, friend.
就像是在说
That's like telegraphing,
"我知道监狱里的烘肉卷的味道"
"I know what prison meatloaf tastes like."
你还是马上后退吧
You just better step back, now.
我就不问你  你知不知道
I'm not gonna ask if you know
被指控犯有侵犯人身罪会怎么样了
what happens when you get charged with assault.
我有种预感  在你家里
I got a hunch you got more mug shots
你的嫌疑犯照片比婴儿照还多
than baby pictures back home.
伙计  你是谁
Man, who are you?
在你因为这件事被逮捕后
I'm the pro-bono suit
你肯定会想聘请我这个无偿律师
you'll try to retain after you go down for this.
连我热心的同事都不会接你的案子
Only not even my soft-hearted partner will take your case,
地狱厨房其他有自尊心的律师也不会接
or any other self-respecting attorney in Hell's Kitchen.
不是因为你有多么惹不起
Not because you're so badass,
而是因为你太蠢
but because you're just that stupid.
你太多嘴了  混蛋
You got a big mouth, asshole.
你忘了  我就靠这个谋生
You forget, I do this for a living.
你看看其他病人的表情
I could ask you to look at the faces of the other patients.
他们每个人都吓得要死
Every last one of 'em scared to death,
就因为你们俩控制不好情绪
because the two of you can't keep it in your pants.
但我觉得  你们谁都不在乎
But I'm guessing that neither one of you
大家的感受
could give a collective shit.
所以我要做律师最擅长的事
So I'm gonna do what attorneys do best
那就是迎合你们自私的本性
and appeal to your selfish natures.
简而言之  如果你们现在
Simply put, if you carve each other up now,
在众目睽睽之下互砍  而且警察就在外面
in front of these witnesses, with cops right outside,
你们就完蛋了
you're screwed!
我不能一走了之
I can't just walk away, man.
我不是让你们移开"我们超认真"的白眼
I'm not asking you to lose the oh-so-serious stink-eye.
别打了
Just don't fight!
放下
Put 'em down.
让这些人做他们该做的吧
Let these people do their jobs.
放下吧
Come on.
你没事吧
You all right?
王八蛋
Son of a bitch.
.357  枪里有一发子弹
.357, one round in the chamber.
有些东西...
Some things, they just...
感觉是那么真切  对吗
They feel right in your hand, huh?
我知道你在想什么  小红
I know what you're thinking, Red.
你可以朝我的胳膊或者腿开枪
You could put a round in my arm, in my leg,
但那都没有用  因为我做好防护了
but it's not gonna work, 'cause I'm all geared up.
只有打爆我的头  才能阻止我
Only way you stop me is with a head shot.
-我不会朝你开枪  -不
- I'm not gonna shoot you. - Nope.
现在还不会
Not yet, you're not.
该让你认清所谓救赎的真面目了
Time to put a face to all your fancy talk about redemption.
艾略特·格罗托  又名格罗托
Elliot Grote, a.k.a. Grotto.
我不想死
I don't wanna die.
你把他怎么样了
What did you do to him?
我抓到这个人渣在偷车  他想跑路
I caught this piece of shit stealing a car, trying to skip town.
我吓坏了  抱歉  我在逃命
I was scared. I'm sorry, I was running for my life.
-闭嘴  -住手  弗兰克
- Shut up. - Stop it, Frank.
你抓住他在偷车
He doesn't deserve to die,
但他罪不至死
just 'cause you caught him stealing cars.
你这么想吗
Is that what you think?
法律说了算  你我说了都不算
It's up to the law, not me and not you!
你给他讲讲你自己的事迹吧
Why don't you tell him a little bit about yourself?
-你无权这么做  -我什么也不是
- You have no right to do this! - I'm nothing.
-我只是个普通人  -是吗  真的吗
- I'm just nobody. - Oh, yeah? That all?
我倒他们的酒  开他们的车
I pour their drinks. I drive their cars.
你几个月之前做的事可不止这些
You were doing a little more than that a few months ago.
你想证明什么  弗兰克
What are you trying to prove, Frank?
-你想向上爬  -不
- You're trying to step up. - No.
-不是吗  -你是谁
- No? - Who are you?
拉法叶街  二层
Lafayette Street, 2nd floor.
你告诉他发生了什么
Why don't you tell him what happened?
求你了  我很抱歉
Please, I'm sorry.
-求你了  我很抱歉  -你快告诉他
- Please, please, I'm sorry. - You tell him now.
弗兰克  我不会射杀你  弗兰克
Frank, I'm not gonna shoot you, Frank.
什么也没发生  抱歉
Nothing happened, I'm sorry.
我再问你最后一遍
I'm only gonna ask you one more time.
我不知道  那就是个地址
I didn't know! It was an address!
我连这个人叫什么都不知道
This guy, I didn't even know his name.
他惹了不该惹的人
He... he got wobbly with the wrong people,
欠了谁什么东西  因为是上头的命令
owed something to somebody, 'cause the order came from on high.
是吗
Yeah?
什么命令
What orders?
-无法拒绝的命令  -快说
- The sort you can't say no to. - Say the words!
你快说  听见没
You say it. Do you hear me?
你不了解这些禽兽
You don't understand these animals.
你不能中途退出  你不能
You can't back out. You can't...
闭嘴  别说了  格罗托
Just shut up! Stop talking, Grotto.
你说
You say it.
我不会问第二遍
I won't ask again.
快说  混蛋
Say the words, asshole!
是我干的  我杀了他  我杀了他
I did it, I killed him! I killed him.
-我朝他脑袋开了两枪  -不
- I put two in his head. - No!
-但我发誓  -该死
- But, I swear to God... - Oh, God damn it.
我并不知道  我并不知道屋里还有个老太太
I didn't know... I didn't know the old lady was in the house.
什么老太太
What old lady?
你干了什么
What did you do?
我不知道她在屋里
I didn't know she was in the house.
她不应该在屋里的
She wasn't supposed to be in the house.
她开始尖叫  我求她别叫了
She started screaming. I begged her to stop.
你干了什么
What did you do?
她看见了我的样子  我没办法
She saw my face. I had no choice.
老太太还有个丈夫  那个男人还有妻儿
Old lady left a husband. Dead man, wife and kids.
你得理解我
You gotta understand me.
我只能那样做
I had to do it.
你还觉得这个人渣不该死吗
You still think this piece of shit is worth saving?
我不会开枪的
I'm not gonna shoot him.
行啊  行
Yeah, okay.
我会的
I will...
如果你没能先杀了我的话
...if you don't kill me first.
找不到  他也不在上城区
Not here. And he's not uptown, either.
停尸房里查不到
Nothing in the morgues.
不论我们的朋友今晚在哪过  也不会是医院
Wherever our friend's spending the night, it ain't in a hospital.
我猜这算是我能得到的最好的消息了
Guess that's as good a news as I'm gonna get.
哥们  对于这样的朋友来说
Hey, man, with friends like these...
他会没事的
He's gonna be fine.
我见识过他的本领
I've seen him in action.
我走了
I'm gonna go.
多谢
Thanks.
知道吗  你很擅长与人交流
You know, you're good with people.
-对啊  我多人见人爱  -我说真的
- Yeah, I'm a real charmer. - I'm serious.
我见过唯一能阻止一场暴徒恶斗的
The only thing I ever saw stop a thug mid-fight...
是一个更厉害的暴徒
was a bigger thug.
是  我喜欢以恶制恶
Yeah, I like to keep it thuggish.
至于我们共同的朋友
And our mutual friend?
我真希望我们俩之间不必走到这一步
I wish things could've been different between us.
他这个人很难懂
He's a very complicated man...
我不需要复杂的人
and that, I don't need.
但也许这个城市需要他
But maybe this city needs him.
我知道他需要你
And I know he needs you.
马特让你走是他的错
Matt made a mistake when he let you go.
你为什么觉得他放手了
What makes you think he did?
-我没耐心了  小红  -你敢开枪
- I'm losing patience, Red. - Don't you dare shoot him.
那主意可不怎么样  他会再开杀戒的
That's a bad idea. You see, he'll kill again.
那事儿忍不了  小红  你能忍吗
Can't live with that, Red. Can you?
我会离开的  不再回来了
I'll leave the city. I won't come back.
闭嘴  闭嘴  开枪啊
Shut up. Shut up. Take the shot.
-去死吧  -太晚了
- Go to hell. - Too late.
你为什么要这样做
Why are you doing this?
因为你需要知道
'Cause you need to understand
像那样的败类会毁掉人们的生活
that pieces of shit like this ruin people's lives.
杀了他也不会让谁起死回生
Killing him's not gonna bring anybody back.
是  但能让他不再伤害别人
No, but it will keep him from hurting anybody else.
不  我发誓我不会再干了
No, I won't do it again, I swear.
我要倒计时了
I'm gonna count down.
-五  -打死他  打死他
- Five... - Look, shoot him. Shoot him!
-四  -开枪啊
- Four... - Look, shoot.
我会亲手把他交给警察的
Hey, I'm gonna hand him over to the police myself.
我会确保他罪有应得  弗兰克
I'm gonna make sure he pays for what he's done, Frank.
-三  -打死他  打啊
- Three... - Shoot him! Do it!
开枪啊  小红  开枪
Take the shot, Red, take the shot.
-不  -你不这么做  就背这条人命吧
- No. - You don't do it, his death's on you.
不论如何  你都是凶手
Either way, you're a killer.
-二  -那算什么选择
- Two... - What kind of choice is that?
那是我每次开枪时的选择
The kind I make every time I pull the trigger.
我现在就要做的选择
The kind I'm gonna make right now.
救救我
Help me.
天啊  我要死了
Oh, God. I'm dying.
-天啊  我要死了  -别动  别动
- God, I'm dying. - Stay still. Stay still.
我救你出去
I'm gonna get you out of here.
不  把我放下来
No, put me down.
你为什么不阻止他
Why didn't you stop him?
对不起
I'm sorry.
什么声音
What the hell was that?
走了  走了
Come on, let's go!
大家跟上  走
Everybody on me. Come on!
走  快走
Let's go! Come on. Let's go!
地狱狂犬
一炉饼干  两炉饼干
One batch, two batch.
你给我一角  我给你一分
Penny and dime.
-他在那儿  -走
- There he is. - Come on!
你完了  小红
You're done, now, Red.
他们来找你算账了
They're coming for you.
你想逃出去的唯一办法就看能不能长出翅膀了
Only way you get out of this, is if you grow wings.
开门  快
Open the goddamn door! Now!
快点
Come on!
-他在那儿  -怎么回事
- There he is! - What the hell's going on?
闭嘴  老头
Shut up, old man.
扔掉枪  扔掉
Drop the gun. Drop it!
-你没事吧  先生  -没事
- You okay, sir? - Yes.
进你房间里  锁上门
Get in your apartment. Lock the door.
那你呢
What about you?
我没事
I'm good.